what is the sum one plus a half plus a
third plus a quarter plus so on to
figure this out let's plot the function
y equals one over X over The Domain C to
c squared then the area one over C plus
one plus one over C plus two plus one
over C plus three and so on up to one
over c squared can be represented by the
area of the rectangles depicted here but
this geometric region contains a
rectangle with area c squared minus C
divided by c squared pictured here so
the sum of one over C plus one up to one
over c squared is greater than or equal
to c squared minus C divided by c
squared which is 1 minus one over C we
can use this fact to see that the sum of
one over C plus one over C plus one up
to one over c squared is greater than or
equal to one applying this result
repeatedly to the harmonic series shows
us one over one is greater than or equal
to one the sum from one half to
one-fourth is greater than or equal to
one the sum from one-fifth to one
twenty-fifth is greater than or equal to
one and so on continuing this process
indefinitely shows us that the harmonic
series diverges as it's greater than an
infinite sum of ones